Guide to the Naum Gabo Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Naum Gabo papers
1920-1980
YCAL MSS 541
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
30.77
(78 boxes)
Collection includes correspondence, writings, and personal papers documenting the professional life of Russian-born artist Naum Gabo. Correspondence features incoming correspondence from other artists, writers, and cultural institutions, arranged alphabetically by correspondent in General Correspondence, but there are also subdivisions for correspondence from family members, projects, finanical and legal instutitions, and unsorted material. Writings in the collection include original work by Gabo, most dating to the latter period of his life in the United States, such as the collection of essays on the fine arts, Of Divers Arts (1962), but also relating to his early The Realistic Manifesto, first published in Russia in 1920 and then in translation in 1957. Other material in the collection includes constructions, drawings, photographs, audiovisual materials, financial and legal records, printed materials, and personal papers, such as passports and family records. Audiovisual materials include audio recordings of talks by Gabo and 8mm and 16mm films of Gabo by Iyla Bolotowsky. In addition to Gabo's papers, there is a small amount of material relating to his older brother Antoine Pevsner.
Gabo, Naum, 1890-1977
Bolotowsky, Ilya, 1907-1981
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Naum Gabo, 1978 and 1980.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 73-74 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 75 (video tape): Use of original is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Associated Materials
Naum Gabo Archive, Tate Britain, London, England.
Naum Gabo Archive, Berlinische Galerie, Berlin, Germany.
Naum Gabo (1890-1977)
Naum Gabo, born Naum Borisovich Pevsner, was a Russian sculptor. Gabo was educated in Russia and Munich before emigrating to Scandinavia in 1915. He then lived in Russia (1917-1922), Germany (19322-1932), France (1932-1935), and England (1936-1946) before emigrating to the United States in 1946 and settling in Connecticut. Gabo is known for his ties to the Constructivist movement. Gabo died in Waterbury, Connecticut, in 1977.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes correspondence, writings, and personal papers documenting the professional life of Russian-born artist Naum Gabo. Correspondence features incoming correspondence from other artists, writers, and cultural institutions, arranged alphabetically by correspondent in General Correspondence, but there are also subdivisions for correspondence from family members, projects, financial and legal institutions, and unsorted material.
Writings in the collection include original work by Gabo, most dating to the latter period of his life in the United States, such as the collection of essays on the fine arts, Of Divers Arts (1962), but also relating to his early The Realistic Manifesto, first published in Russia in 1920 and then in translation in 1957.
Other material in the collection includes constructions (models), drawings, photographs, audio-visual materials, financial and legal records, printed materials, and personal papers, such as passports and family records. Audiovisual materials include audio recordings of talks by Gabo and 8 and 16mm films of Gabo by Ilya Bolotowsky.
In addition to Gabo's papers, there is a small amount of material relating to his older brother Antoine Pevsner.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: I. Correspondence, 1939-1980. II. Writings, 1920-1975. III. Other Material, 1955-1977. IV. Material Relating to Antoine Pevsner, undated.
Artists; Constructivism (Art); Sculptors; Sculpture, Modern -- 20th Century; Film (material by form); Photographic prints; Sound recordings; Video recordings; Artists; Sculptors; Bolotowsky, Ilya, 1907-1981; Gabo, Naum, 1890-1977; Pevsner, Antoine, 1886-1962
- Correspondence, 1939-1980; Series I; 16.06; (40 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into seven major subseries: General Correspondence, Dictations, Projects, Family, Unsorted Correspondence, Financial Correspondence and Material, and Legal and Other Correspondence.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I. Correspondence, features incoming correspondence from artists and writers, art critics and collectors, publishers, cultural institutions and organizations, such as museums, galleries, and foundations, and others. Large files exist for the Bollingen Foundation, advertising agent Marcus Brumwell, publisher Lund Humphries Ltd, art critics Marcel Joray and Sir Herbert Read, Lewis Mumford, artist and curator Willem Sandberg, curator James Johnson Sweeney, and the Tate Gallery in London, among others. There are smaller files for numerous well-known early Twentieth century artists, including Anni and Joseph Albers, Hans Arp, Henri Cartier-Bresson, Ivan and Serge Chermayeff, Katherine Dreier, Marcel Duchamps, Walter Gropius, Hans Richter, and Kurt Schwitters.
  The series includes correspondence from family members and relating to projects and financial and legal matters, as well as unsorted material.
  Correspondence is chiefly in English, with material in French, German, and Russian.
  - General Correspondence
    - Abrams, Harry N. (Box 1)
    - Adams, Bernard (Box 1)
    - Addison Gallery of American Art, Philips Academy, Andover, Mass., 8 (Box 1)
    - Adrian, P.G. (Box 1)
    - Advocates for the Arts (Box 1)
    - Akron Art Institute (Box 1)
    - Albers, Anni (Box 1)
    - Albers, Joseph (Box 1)
    - American Art Expositions, Inc. New York (Box 1)
    - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters (Box 1)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box 1)
    - American Association for the United Nations (Box 1)
    - American Embassy, London (Box 1)
    - American Embassy, Montreal (Box 1)
    - American Embassy, Moscow-Washington (Box 1)
    - American Federation of Arts, 3 (Box 1)
    - American University, Washington D.C. (Box 1)
    - Anderson, Troels (Box 1)
    - Andreasen (Box 1)
    - Andrews, Michael F. (Box 1)
    - Architectural Association, London (Box 1)
    - Architectural Forum, New York (Box 1)
    - Architectural League of New York (Box 1)
    - Architects' Year Book, No. IV, London (Box 1)
    - Architectural Record, New York (Box 1)
    - Architectural Review, London, 2 (Box 1)
    - Archives of American Art (Box 1)
    - Arnason, Harvard H. (Box 1)
    - Arp, Hans [Jean] (Box 1)
    - Arp-Teaber, Sophia (?) (Box 1)
    - Art D'Aujourd'hui, 3 (Box 1)
    - Art Dealer's Association, New York (Box 1)
    - The Art Exhibitions Bureau, London (Box 1)
    - Art Forum (Box 1)
    - Art in America, New York (Box 1)
    - The Art Institute of Chicago, 6 (Box 1)
    - Art News, New York, 2 (Box 1)
    - Art Research Centre Group (Box 1)
    - Artists Equity Association: New England Chapter (Box 1)
    - The Arts Club of Chicago, 5 (Box 1)
    - Arts Council of Great Britain, 4 (Box 1)
    - Arts Magazine, New York (Box 1)
    - Associated Talking Pictures (Box 1)
    - Augustine, Paula (Box 1)
    - Augustine and Schoonman, 7 (Box 2)
    - Austin, A. Everett and Helen (Box 2)
    - A-Ad General (Box 2)
    - Ae-Al General (Box 2)
    - Am-Az General (Box 2)
    - B General (Box 2)
    - Ba General (Box 2)
    - Be General (Box 2)
    - Bi General (Box 2)
    - Bi-Bo General (Box 2)
    - Bo-Bt General (Box 2)
    - Bu-Bz General (Box 2)
    - Babitskii, Arkady (Box 2)
    - Bagier, Guido, Dr. (Box 2)
    - Bakels, A.C. (Box 2)
    - Ballets Russes (Box 2)
    - Photographic Material: Baltimore (Box 2)
    - Baltimore Museum of Art, 5 (Box 2)
    - Baltimore Project for Purchase of Head for Urban Location (Box 2)
    - Baltimore, City of [Information sheets etc. promotion council], 2 (Box 2)
    - Baltimore, City of [Information re: developments] (Box 2)
    - Bann, S. (Box 2)
    - Barnes Foundation (Box 2)
    - Barooshian, Vahan (Box 2)
    - Barran, Fritz (Box 2)
    - Basle, Kunstialle (Box 2)
    - Beachcroft & Co., London (Box 2)
    - Behne, A. (Box 2)
    - Belgian Television (Box 2)
    - Benjamin, Walter (Box 2)
    - Benkert (Box 2)
    - Benthall (Box 2)
    - Berlack, Israels & Liberman, 2 (Box 2)
    - Berlin, Sven (Box 2)
    - Berlin, Nationalgalerie, 5 (Box 2)
    - Berliner Illustrirte Zeitung (Box 3)
    - Bern, Kunsthalle (Box 3)
    - Bernal, Professor J. Desmond (Box 3)
    - Galerie Claude Bernard, 2 (Box 3)
    - Bernath (Box 3)
    - Galerie Beyeler (Box 3)
    - Biederman, Charles (Box 3)
    - Bier, J. (Box 3)
    - Bill, Max (Box 3)
    - Birkbeck, Montagu (Box 3)
    - Birkbeck, Montagu's and Co., 7 (Box 3)
    - Birmingham Art Association (Box 3)
    - Birmingham Museum of Art (Box 3)
    - Birrell, Verna (Box 3)
    - Black, Misha (Box 3)
    - Bland (Box 3)
    - Block, Dr. (Box 3)
    - Bloomstrann, Irving (Box 3)
    - Board of Trade, London (Box 3)
    - Boas, Simone (Box 3)
    - Bohm, D. (Box 3)
    - National Gallery, Washington - Bollingen (Box 3)
    - Bollingen Foundation, 16 (Box 3)
    - Bolotowsky (Box 3)
    - Borchers and Jurges Nache (Box 3)
    - Boston (Box 3)
    - Boston Art Festival (Box 3)
    - Bostroem, Anne (Box 3)
    - Bostroem, Fedor Ivanovich (Box 3)
    - Bostroem, Kyra (Box 3)
    - Bourlet, James Bourlet and Sons, London, 3 (Box 3)
    - Boustedt, Bo, 12 (Box 4)
    - Bouwcentrom (Box 4)
    - Bouwkamp, Jack and Marianne, 2 (Box 4)
    - Bowlt, 2 (Box 4)
    - Bozo, Dominique (Box 4)
    - Brandeis University, 2 (Box 4)
    - Brawne, Michael (Box 4)
    - Braziller (Box 4)
    - Breest, Kurt (Box 4)
    - Breit, Guy (Box 4)
    - Brett, Mitchell Collection (Box 4)
    - Breuer, Marcel (Box 4)
    - British Airways (Box 4)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation, London, 10 (Box 4)
    - British Embassy, Washington (Box 4)
    - British Museum, London (Box 4)
    - Brodsky, Joseph (Box 4)
    - Bronowski (Box 4)
    - Margaret Brown Gallery, Boston (Box 4)
    - Brown University, 2 (Box 4)
    - Brumwell (Stuart Advertising Agency), 3 (Box 4)
    - Brumwell, Marcus, 16 (Box 4)
    - Brussels - 1958 International Exhibition (Box 5)
    - Bryn Mawr (Box 5)
    - Buchanon, George (Box 5)
    - Buchanon, John (Box 5)
    - Bucher (Box 5)
    - Budapest, Literary Museum "Petofi" (Box 5)
    - Budworth and Co. (Box 5)
    - Buffalo, Alright Knox Gallery, 11 (Box 5)
    - Bumpus, John and Edward Bumpus Ltd. (Box 5)
    - Burchard, John (Box 5)
    - Burckhardt, Rudolph (Box 5)
    - P. Burlin (Box 5)
    - Burliuk, David (Box 5)
    - Burnett, Mrs. Joan (Box 5)
    - Burnham, Jack, 2 (Box 5)
    - Burton Insurance Agency (Box 5)
    - Cairns, Huntington (Box 5)
    - California, University of (Box 5)
    - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (Box 5)
    - Canadian Corporation for the 1967 World Exhibition, 3 (Box 5)
    - Carlisle, Olga (Box 5)
    - Cartier-Bresson, Henri (Box 5)
    - Carvalmo, Flavio De R. (Box 5)
    - Cassidy, Edward (Box 5)
    - Castelli, Leo (Box 5)
    - Causton, Bernard (Box 5)
    - Chambers, W.W. (Box 5)
    - Chanin (Box 5)
    - Chapman College (Box 5)
    - Chase, A. Elizabeth (Box 5)
    - Chelsea Arts Club (Box 5)
    - Chermayeff, Ivan (Box 5)
    - Chermayeff, Serge, 4 (Box 5)
    - Chipp, Herschel B. (Box 5)
    - Chowdhury, Roy (Box 5)
    - The Christian Science Monitor, 2 (Box 5)
    - Chudzicki, Eugeniusz (Box 5)
    - The Cincinnati Art Museum (Box 5)
    - The Cincinnati Modern Art Museum (Box 5)
    - Clarke, Graham (Box 5)
    - Clark University, Worcester, MA (Box 5)
    - Clay, Jean, 3 (Box 5)
    - The Cleveland Museum of Art, 2 (Box 5)
    - Cochrane, Alexander S. (Box 5)
    - Coloene, Wellrat - Richartz Museum (Box 5)
    - Cohen and Powell, 11 (Box 6)
    - Cohen, Arthur A. (Box 6)
    - Cohen, Leonie (Mrs. Paul Findlay) (Box 6)
    - College Art Association of America (Box 6)
    - Collingridge, Alan (Box 6)
    - Columbia University, New York (Box 6)
    - Columbia University, Teachers College (Box 6)
    - Columbus Gallery of Fine Arts (Box 6)
    - Connaissance Des Arts, Paris (Box 6)
    - Connecticut Academy (Box 6)
    - Connecticut College, New London, CT (Box 6)
    - Connecticut Commission on the Arts (Box 6)
    - Connecticut Development Commission, Hartford (Box 6)
    - Convegio Internazionale Artist, Critici E Studiosi D'Arte, Verucchio, Italy (Box 6)
    - Cooke, Francis and May May, 3 (Box 6)
    - Cooke, Francis, The family of (Box 6)
    - Cooke, Hereward Lester (Box 6)
    - Cooke, The Hereward Lester Cooke Foundation (Box 6)
    - Copyright Office, Library of Congress (Box 6)
    - Cornell University: Herbert F. Johnson (Box 6)
    - Cornell University: Andrew Dickson White (Box 6)
    - Cornford, Christopher (Box 6)
    - Covenant Insurance (Box 6)
    - Cox, Langford, Stoddard and Cutter (Box 6)
    - Cox, Shelby Shackeford and Richard (Box 6)
    - Frank Crystal and Co., NY Insurance, 7 (Box 6)
    - Cunningham, Charles (Box 6)
    - Cushman, Dr. George (Box 6)
    - Czechoslovak Institute (Box 6)
    - Conn.: various documents relating to the State of Connecticut or major businesses there (Box 6)
    - Ca-Col General (Box 6)
    - Cons-Cz General (Box 6)
    - Daedalus (Box 7)
    - Dahlberg, Edward (Box 7)
    - Dallas Museum of Fine Art (Box 7)
    - Danes, Gibson A. (Box 7)
    - Davis, Douglas (Box 7)
    - D'Harnancourt (Box 7)
    - Debrunner, Hugo, 4 (Box 7)
    - De Cordova Museum, Lincoln (Box 7)
    - Delahaye (Box 7)
    - Delamanty Institute (Box 7)
    - Denver Arts Museum (Box 7)
    - Department of Health, Education and Welfare (Box 7)
    - Derenberg, Walter (Box 7)
    - De Sujo (Box 7)
    - Detroit Institute of Art, 2 (Box 7)
    - Deutsche Glastechnische Gesellschaft (Box 7)
    - Dewar, Margaret (Box 7)
    - De Weese (Box 7)
    - Diaghilev, Serge (Box 7)
    - Diamond, Harold (Box 7)
    - Dictaphone (Box 7)
    - The Dime Savings Bank (Box 7)
    - Dobree, Valentine (Box 7)
    - Domela (Box 7)
    - Dorner, Alexander (Box 7)
    - Dorner, Lydia (Box 7)
    - Drayer, Walter (Box 7)
    - Dreier, Katherine, 3 (Box 7)
    - Dreier, Katherine photocopies of correspondence from Gabo Archive (Box 7)
    - Drexel Institute of Technology, Philadelphia, PA (Box 7)
    - Duarte, Antonio and Regine, 10 (Box 7)
    - Duchamp, Marcel (Box 7)
    - Duchamp, Teeny (Box 7)
    - Duckworth, Sir Arthur, 2 (Box 7)
    - Duhamel (Box 7)
    - Duisberg, Wilhelm-Lehmbruce (Box 7)
    - Duke University, North Carolina (Box 7)
    - Da-D General (Box 7)
    - De-Dn General (Box 7)
    - Do-Dz General (Box 7)
    - East Cleveland Museum Galleries (Box 8)
    - Eastman and Eastman, 6 (Box 8)
    - Eates, Margot, 2 (Box 8)
    - Ede, James, 4 (Box 8)
    - Edwards, Oscar, 6 (Box 8)
    - Eindhoven, Stedelijk Von Abbemuseum (Box 8)
    - Einstein, Albert (Box 8)
    - Ellis, Aidan (Box 8)
    - Elsevier (Box 8)
    - Elzas, Abram (Box 8)
    - Encyclopedia Britannica (Box 8)
    - Estorick, S. (Box 8)
    - Estrada, Marguerite (Box 8)
    - Ea-Ej General (Box 8)
    - Experiments in Air and Technology Incorporated (Box 8)
    - Ei-Ez General (Box 8)
    - Fabbri, Fratelli Fabbri Editori, Milan (Box 8)
    - Faber and Faber, 3 (Box 8)
    - Family Publications Service (Box 8)
    - Farm and Wilderness Camp (Box 8)
    - Fawcett, James (Box 8)
    - Feigen, Richard Feigen Gallery, Chicago (Box 8)
    - Ferry, W. Hawkins (Box 8)
    - Ferstenberg, P. (Box 8)
    - Festival D'Art D'Avant-Garde, Paris (Box 8)
    - Field Enterprises (Box 8)
    - Fitzgibbon, James (Box 8)
    - Flanagan, George (Box 8)
    - Felchine, Serge and Mollie (Box 8)
    - Florack, Peter (Box 8)
    - Focus International Book Production (Box 8)
    - Foester, Horst (Box 8)
    - Fogg Museum of Art, Harvard University, Cambridge (Including correspondence from Wade White), 2 (Box 8)
    - Ford Foundation, 2 (Box 8)
    - Fortnum and Mason, London (Box 8)
    - Foster, Norman (Box 8)
    - Foundation for Contemporary Performance Arts, New York (Box 8)
    - Frank Travel Service (Box 8)
    - Frankfurt Am Main (Box 8)
    - Frankfurter Kunstverein (Box 8)
    - Freeman, Joseph (Box 8)
    - Freund, Meyer H. (Box 8)
    - Fried, Rose, 2 (Box 9)
    - Fuller, Sue (Box 9)
    - Fa-Foc General (Box 9)
    - For-Fz General (Box 9)
    - Galerie Charpentier, Paris (Box 9)
    - Galerie Drouin, Paris (Box 9)
    - Galerie Denise Rene, Paris (Box 9)
    - Galerie Louis Carre, Paris (Box 9)
    - Gallatin, A.E. (Box 9)
    - The Gallery of Modern Art, Columbus Circle, New York (Box 9)
    - Galston, Alexandra Korsakoff, 2 (Box 9)
    - Gardiner, Margaret (Box 9)
    - Garrison, Lee (Box 9)
    - Geron, Jean-Marie (Box 9)
    - Otto Gerson Gallery, 4 (Box 9)
    - Gibbons, Cedric (Box 9)
    - Gibson, William (Box 9)
    - Giedion, Dr. S. and Giedion-Weicker, Carola (Box 9)
    - Glarner, Fritz (Box 9)
    - Goldfinger, Ursula (Box 9)
    - Goodman, Alice and Benny (Box 9)
    - Gorny, Hein (Box 9)
    - Gorodetzky, Serge (Box 9)
    - Goucher College, Towson, Baltimore (Box 9)
    - Graham, W.C. & Co., Inc. (Box 9)
    - Gray, Basil (Box 9)
    - Gray, Camilla (Box 9)
    - Gray, Cleve (and wife Francine), 2 (Box 9)
    - Gray, Nicolette (Box 9)
    - Green, Christopher (Box 9)
    - Gregory, Eric Craven (Box 9)
    - Griffiths, Joan (Box 9)
    - Gropius, Walter (Box 9)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 3 (Box 9)
    - Guggenheim, Peggy (Box 9)
    - Solomon R. Guggenheim Foundation, New York (Box 9)
    - Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum, 3 (Box 9)
    - Ga-Gh General (Box 9)
    - Gi-Gn General (Box 9)
    - Go-Gra General (Box 9)
    - Gre-Gz General (Box 9)
    - Habasque, Guy (Box 10)
    - Hamilton, George Heard and Polly, 5 (Box 10)
    - Paul Hamlyn Publishers (Box 10)
    - Hammacher, Arno (Box 10)
    - Hannover, Kunstverein (Box 10)
    - Hanover Gallery, London (Box 10)
    - Haring, Hugo Von (Box 10)
    - Harrison, Wallace, 2 (Box 10)
    - Hartford Times (Box 10)
    - Harvard University: Carpenter Center for the Visual Arts (Box 10)
    - Harvard University: Graduate School of Design, 5 (Box 10)
    - Harvard University: College Library (Box 10)
    - Harvard University: Misc. (Box 10)
    - Harvard University Press (Box 10)
    - Havinden, Ashley (Box 10)
    - D.C. Heath and Company, Boston (Box 10)
    - Heller, Judith (Box 10)
    - Henderson, J. Welles (Box 10)
    - Hendy, Philip (Box 10)
    - Hepworth, Barbara, 2 (Box 10)
    - Herbert, Professor Robert (Box 10)
    - Heron, Patrick (Box 10)
    - Hessel, Jos. (Box 10)
    - Hilberseimer, L. (Box 10)
    - Hildebrandt, Professor Hans (Box 10)
    - Hill, Anthony, 2 (Box 10)
    - Hirshorn, Joseph H. (Box 10)
    - Hofmann, Dr. Werner (Box 10)
    - Holohan, Elizabeth (Box 10)
    - Holland America Line (Box 10)
    - Home Office, Great Britain (Box 10)
    - Horizon (Box 10)
    - House, Gordon (Box 10)
    - Houston, The Museum of Fine Arts of Houston (Box 10)
    - Ha-Has General (Box 10)
    - Hat-He General (Box 10)
    - Ho-Hd General (Box 10)
    - I. A. C. (Box 11)
    - I. C. A., 4 (Box 11)
    - University of Illinois (Box 11)
    - Illinois Institute of Design (Box 11)
    - Impressions Workshop, Boston (Box 11)
    - Ince, Ruth (Box 11)
    - Inland Revenue of Great Britain (Box 11)
    - Innes, Tullah (Box 11)
    - Institute of Contemporary Arts: Washington, 2 (Box 11)
    - Internal Revenue Service (Box 11)
    - International Association of Plastic Arts (Box 11)
    - International Institute of Arts and Letters (Box 11)
    - International Sculpture Conference, 3 (Box 11)
    - International Visual Aids Center, Brussels (Box 11)
    - Institute of International Education, 3 (Box 11)
    - Iowa, University of (Box 11)
    - Israel Museum, Jerusalem (Box 11)
    - Istituto Della Enciclopedia Italiana (Box 11)
    - Ivins, Barbara (Box 11)
    - Ivins, William, 3 (Box 11)
    - Izdebsky-Pritzhard, Aline (Box 11)
    - I General (Box 11)
    - Janis, Harriet (Box 12)
    - Japolsky, N. (Box 12)
    - Javiscas, Gabriel (Box 12)
    - Jensen, Alfred, 2 (Box 12)
    - Jespersen, Gunnar (Box 12)
    - Jewish Museum, New York (Box 12)
    - John, Grace (Box 12)
    - Johnson, Ronald (Box 12)
    - Johnson, Lyndon B. (Box 12)
    - Joray, Marcel, 12 (Box 12)
    - Jordan, Jim (Box 12)
    - Ja-Jn General (Box 12)
    - Jo-Jz General (Box 12)
    - Kansas, University of (Box 12)
    - Karsh, Yosuf (Box 12)
    - Karsten, Charles (Box 12)
    - Kassak, Ludwig/Lajos (Box 12)
    - Kassel, Documenta Exhibitions (Box 12)
    - Keating and Co. (Box 12)
    - Keller, Dr. Florence (Box 12)
    - Kennedy, John F. (Box 12)
    - Kennedy, Robert (Box 12)
    - Kepes, Gyorgy, 3 (Box 12)
    - Kimball, Mrs. J.D. (Box 12)
    - M. Knoedler & Co., Inc., New York (Box 12)
    - Kochno, Boris (Box 12)
    - Kohn, Bernard (Box 12)
    - Kosice (Box 12)
    - Kostka, Bob (Box 12)
    - Krauss, Rosalind (Box 12)
    - Kruger, Werner (Box 12)
    - Kuh, Katherine (Box 12)
    - Kuljerman, Dr. Udo (Box 12)
    - Kuylenstierna, Krister (Box 12)
    - Kvikne's Motel, Balholm (Box 12)
    - Ka-Kb General (Box 12)
    - Kb-Kn General (Box 12)
    - Ko-Kz General (Box 12)
    - Lambert, Phyllis B. (Box 13)
    - Lamis, Leroy (Box 13)
    - Lane, Alvin S. (Box 13)
    - James Lanham Ltd., St. Ives (Box 13)
    - Lanier, Picataqua (Box 13)
    - Lanyon, Peter, 2 (Box 13)
    - Lanyon, Sheila (Box 13)
    - Leach, Bernard, 4 (Box 13)
    - Lefebvre-Foinet, Lucien (Box 13)
    - Lefebvre-Foinet, Paris (Box 13)
    - Alex Reed and Lefevre Ltd., London, 2 (Box 13)
    - Lefkowitz, Louis J. & Rothman, Joseph, 5 (Box 13)
    - Lehnert, Dr., Berlin (Box 13)
    - Lehning, Arthur (Box 13)
    - Leicester Galleries, London (Box 13)
    - "Leonardo" (Box 13)
    - Julian Levy Gallery (Box 13)
    - Lewis, David (Box 13)
    - Lippman, Walter (Box 13)
    - Lippold, Richard (Box 13)
    - Lisbon: Fundacao Calouste Gulbenrian (Box 13)
    - Lista, Giovanni (Box 13)
    - "The Listener", London (Box 13)
    - Little Review and Little Review Gallery, New York (Box 13)
    - Livre De Poche, Paris (Box 13)
    - Lloyds Bank, London and St. Ives (Box 13)
    - Lobato, Guimares [Louis] (Box 13)
    - London Gallery (Box 13)
    - London School of Economics (Box 13)
    - Lostetter, Alvern (Box 13)
    - Louisiana Collection of Danish Arts and Craft, Humbleback, Denmark (Box 13)
    - Louisiana, 14 (Box 13)
    - Lousada, Anthony B. and Pat (Box 13)
    - Lowenstein, Janey H., 2 (Box 13)
    - Lowenstein, Mandy (Box 13)
    - Lowenstein, Tom (Box 13)
    - Leighton, Clare (Box 13)
    - Lucas, Caroline (Box 13)
    - Ludwigshafen Am Rhein, Stadt Ver Waltung (Box 13)
    - Lutz, Dr. F.A. (Box 13)
    - Lund, Sweden, 3 (Box 14)
    - Lund Humphries Ltd., 19 (Box 14)
    - La-Ld General (Box 14)
    - Le-Lh General (Box 14)
    - Li-Ln General (Box 14)
    - Lo-Lt General (Box 14)
    - Lu-Lz General (Box 14)
    - Ma-Md General (Box 14)
    - Mac-Mc General (Box 14)
    - Me-Mic General (Box 14)
    - Mid-Moo General (Box 14)
    - Mos -Mz General (Box 14)
    - McAlpine, R. Alistair (Box 14)
    - MacAgy, Douglas (Box 14)
    - R.H.H. Macaulay (Box 14)
    - McAuslan, Helen (Box 14)
    - McCrory Corporation, New York (Box 14)
    - McGuire, William (Box 14)
    - McKee, Douglas (Box 14)
    - Mabey, Marion (Box 14)
    - Maeght Editeur, Paris (Box 14)
    - Magazine of Art, New York (Box 14)
    - Marlborough, 25 (Box 15)
    - Marlborough, 17 (Box 16)
    - Marnau, Fred (Box 17)
    - Martianoff Bookstore (Box 17)
    - Martin, Sir Leslie, 3 (Box 17)
    - Martin, Lady (Sadie), 3 (Box 17)
    - Martin, Christopher (Kit) (Box 17)
    - Martin, Susan (Box 17)
    - Marx, Samuel (Box 17)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Mass., 3 (Box 17)